SIAMAK SHAMS

07789934114 | siamak.shams@gmail.com | British

SUMMARY

I'm a DevOps trainer, agile coach and transformation consultant. For the past 15 years I've delivered professional IT training with a specific focus on technical transformation covering; Agile, DevOps, Operating Systems, Languages, Cloud Platforms, PaaS, SaaS, CI/CD, Testing and Test Strategy, Web and Mobile applications development and the related technologies. The DevOps / Agile Transformation training included training and coaching organisations and teams in the mind-set and the methods for digital transformation. Prior to that period I have held positions including developer, senior developer, system and software architect, team lead, and department manager.

Roles

- Technical Trainer
- Transformation Consultant (Agile Coach and Trainer),
- Delivery Manager,
- Scrum Master,
- Team Leader,
- Lead Developer,
- Developer and Tester

Technical Skills

- Docker/Docker-Compose
- Terraform
- Languages: Python, C#, Java, PHP, JavaScript,
- Node.js, Express with various view engines,
- Play with Java, HTML
- Jekyll with Markdown and Liquid
- Testing Tools,
- Git/Github,
- Jenkins,
- Selenium,
- Linux and Windows OS.

Professional Certifications

- AWS Associate Certifications.
- Certified Scrum Master (CSM) Scrum Alliance
- Certified Scrum Professional (CSP) Scrum Alliance
- Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I) Scrum Org
- Accredited Kanban Trainer (LKU)
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) .NET Web-Applications

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Information Systems, Operationalisation of Agile at Organisations, Brunel University - London UK

MSc, Software Engineering, "Object Oriented Analysis, Design and Programming in C++", University of Westminster - London UK

EXPERIENCE

HMRC MDTP 2018 – Present

DevOps Trainer

I'm a DevOps Trainer for the Civil Service Fast Track Apprenticeship programme (a two-year Level 4 higher apprenticeship) for the HMRC Multichannel Digital Tax Platform (MDTP). The MDTP gives access to digital tax products that allow British citizens and companies to manage their tax affairs. The MDTP is a Platform As A Service (PaaS) that hosts 100+ Scala/Play Microservices that represent 20+ citizen and company tax products.

My role includes the specification and planning of the apprenticeship programme syllabus, group and individual learning-by-doing objectives, and the day-to-day training and mentoring of the apprentices for meeting their goals.

Infoglow 2016 – 2017

<u>Digital Transformation Consultant / Agile Practitioner and Coach</u>

Transformation Consultant – Delivering solutions for clients such as JATO, Cognizant and Equal Experts.

Trayport 2013 – 2016

CTO

As CTO may mandate was to transform and implement the organisation's operation to Agile / DevOps way of working. This was a hands-on role that included duties such as Process Improvement, Scrum Master, and communication with other directors and department heads for scaling Agile practices across the organisation including creation of complete Agile / DevOps teams.

Infoglow 2011 –2013

<u>Technical</u> / Agile Trainer

Support Clients' Technical / Agile Transformation. Clients Included: HSBC, Tesco PLC, Societe Generale - Corporate & Investment Banking.

RADTAC Ltd Associate 2007 - 2011

RADTAC Associate: Technical / Agile Trainer – Snr Software Developer - Scrum Master

Clients included: City Index, Family Investment, Landmark Information Group, CallScripter, British Energy - Power and Energy Trading.